Data protection and disclaimer
==============================

Anchor Navigation
-----------------

Data protection
---------------

When visiting this website, using the Swiss Post Customer Center login (hereafter referred to as “login”), using Swiss Post apps or using Swiss Post apps that are offered online (hereafter referred to as “online services” \[e.g. microsites\]), data is collected. These services will hereinafter be referred to as “digital presence”.

Depending on the use of the digital presence, personal data will be processed by Swiss Post Ltd, Post CH Ltd, Post CH Communication Ltd and Post CH Network Ltd (collectively referred to as “Swiss Post,” “we,” or “us”).

More information about Swiss Post Ltd and its companies can be found on our [About us](https://www.post.ch/en/about-us) page.

We regard the protection of your personal data as a very important matter. We therefore treat your personal data with great care and in accordance with the relevant statutory provisions of data protection law and postal legislation.

In this Privacy Policy, we inform you about our data processing methods. We explain which data is processed by us whenever you access this website and other digital presences.

### 1\. Who owns the data that is collected?

Swiss Post Ltd is the provider of the website and login, and as the owner of the relevant data collections, may make decisions about their purpose and content. For each online service, the service provider indicated in the description is the owner. 

### 2\. What data do we collect?

In principle, our publicly accessible digital presence can be used without requiring you to disclose any personal data. An exception to this, as is common practice with many websites, is certain data (such as IP addresses and other usage information) which is collected automatically by our web analytics software and then analysed and processed. By using our digital presence, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of this data in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

#### 2.1 Automatic logging

Our web servers automatically log every visit in a temporary log file. User-specific data (such as the identification data of the browser used, the operating system of the requesting computer, the amount of data transferred, the name of the Internet Service Provider, the date and time of access) and technical data (such as the name and URL of the referring web page, if the website was accessed via a link and, in addition, the search term if the website was accessed via a search engine) are logged and analysed anonymously. First and foremost, this data is needed to enable the use of our content (connection set-up), and is also used for internal, system-related purposes – such as technical administration and system security – and optimizing your search experience. As part of this, so-called cookies may be used (see section 4 below). IP addresses are used for automated security checks, e.g. automatically verified to combat fraud and immediately deleted. Furthermore, IP addresses are used for analytics purposes. In particular, Google Analytics anonymizes the IPs received immediately and processes the anonymized IP addresses only for the analysis (see section 6).

We do not use your data for any other purposes, unless you have given your consent to additional data processing when using certain services, or if we are legally bound to do so.

#### 2.2 Additional data processing

In order to use some of our online services, you must first register for the login with some personal data. When using the services, the data is processed in accordance with a contractual agreement and the associated Subscriber Conditions (SC) or General Terms and Conditions (GTC).

When using the Swiss Post Voice App to access the “My consignments” online service, your voice input will be converted into text. This text will then be queried in the Swiss Post systems and the required information will be shared. To initialize the application, you must log in with your Swiss Post login or SwissID. Swiss Post will process the data solely for the purpose of providing the service and, in an anonymized manner, for the purpose of improving the quality of the service.

Data will also be processed by Google or Amazon. This affects only data that is transferred to Google or Amazon by your mobile phone or supported device. Swiss Post itself transfers data to Google or Amazon only when it is necessary to do so for processing the query and when requested by the customer. Data processing by Google or Amazon is outside the influence and responsibility of Swiss Post. Please familiarize yourself with Google or Amazon’s data protection provisions and the possible settings relating to the voice-controlled assistant.

In addition, we process personal data if you decide to send it to us; for example, by filling out an online form or sending us a message via our contact forms. In these cases, we will only ask you to provide the personal data we require to perform the services we offer. The information you provide will be recorded in our IT systems.

### 3. How do we use your data?

Collecting data helps us to continue developing and improving our digital presence and to optimize our range of services. We use the data collected by automatic logging for the following purposes:

*   To enable you to use our digital presence (by establishing a connection).
*   For internal management of the website, for example technical administration and maintenance of system security.
*   To optimize user friendliness, we collect statistics on user behaviour on our website. This data is analysed (see also section 4.4).
*   To provide logins, online services and contractually-compliant processing of these services.
*   To tailor our websites to specific target groups (with targeted content or information on the website that may be of interest to you).
*   To prevent fraud and improve the security of the website.
*   To serve you with personalized adverts on our digital presence based on data from third parties.

We also use so-called re-targeting or re-marketing methods on our websites. These are online marketing tools. If you visit other third-party websites, you will then be shown product recommendations with targeted pop-up adverts. In order to achieve an optimized result for you in this regard, data is also transmitted to third-party providers who may also be domiciled abroad.

If services from Swiss Post are used, your data is also processed in accordance with the contractual agreement and the Subscriber Conditions (SC) or General Terms and Conditions (GTC).

### 4\. What role do cookies play?

#### 4.1 What is a cookie?

A cookie is a text file with short data sequences (a sequence of letters and numbers) that by itself cannot perform any operations. This text file is transferred to your browser by the web server when you visit a website. The cookie is stored on your local computer. There are two different types of cookie: temporary cookies and permanent cookies. We use both temporary cookies, which are automatically deleted from your mobile device or computer at the end of the browser session, and permanent cookies, which remain on your computer or mobile device for up to ten years after the browser session. They are automatically disabled after the programmed time.

You can check your browser’s log at any time to see which cookies are being run.

#### 4.2 How safe is it to enable cookies?

It is safe to enable cookies when visiting our digital presence. When using a third-party computer, however, we recommend deleting cookies and the history in the browser you are using to prevent subsequent users from being able to retrace your surfing behaviour.

#### 4.3 How do we use cookies?

We use cookies to carry out an analysis of general user behaviour. Our goal is to optimize our digital presence, make it easier to use, make finding content more intuitive and ensure that it is laid out and structured more clearly. We are keen to make our digital presence user friendly in accordance with your requirements. This allows us to optimize our websites with targeted content or information on the website that may be of interest to you (e.g. geolocated).

#### 4.4 How do we use cookies from third-party providers (third-party cookies)?

We use selected cookies from third-party providers (so-called third-party cookies). These cookies are intended to optimize the user experience, [display personalized advertising](https://www.post.ch/en/pages/programmatic-ads) (Google Ad Manager) or prevent fraud. We draw attention to our use of cookies via a cookie banner. You have the ability to prevent the use of cookies at any time via the cookie settings in your browser (see section 7 below).

### 5\. Social media

On certain sites we use the Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and XING sharing functions.

This allows you to share individual content. The individual social network’s data protection provisions apply to the processing of this data.

### 6\. What web analytics services do we use?

We use different web analytics services such as AT Internet, Hotjar, Siteimprove, Fusedeck, AppsFlyer and Google Analytics for selected applications. The web analytics services use cookies (see section 4.1), which evaluate the use of the digital presence in order to obtain information and improve our services and in order to provide a statistical evaluation of our visitor traffic. It is not possible for us to trace the identity of individuals during these operations, unless you logged in using the Swiss Post Customer Login and did not subsequently delete the cookie. The information generated in this way may be transmitted to a server abroad and stored there. You can prevent cookies from being stored by adjusting the settings of your browser software accordingly (see section 7). Data collection and storage can be withdrawn at any time with future effect. You can find more information in the privacy statements of [AT Internet](https://www.atinternet.com/en/company/data-protection/), [Siteimprove](https://siteimprove.com/en/privacy/), [Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy/), [Fusedeck](https://fusedeck.com/data-privacy/), [AppsFlyer](https://www.appsflyer.com/privacy-policy/) and [Google Analytics.](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en)

### 7\. How do I prevent the use of cookies and web analytics tools?

The use of cookies can be managed via the browser functions (settings or add-ons).

Most browsers accept cookies automatically. However, you can instruct your browser not to accept any cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from a website you visit. You can also delete cookies on your computer or mobile device using the corresponding function in your browser.

To enable or disable cookies in your web browser:

Check which web browser you are using and then select the relevant link below. On the page you are taken to, you will find instructions on how to enable or disable cookies in your web browser.

If you choose not to accept our cookies or the cookies and tools of our partner companies, you will not be able to see certain information on our websites and will be unable to use some functions that improve your visit.

You can find more information on the use of cookies at the following website: [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) 

### 8. Will we share your data with anyone else?

In the event that Swiss Post engages third parties to provide the services, it will be authorized to make available to them the data necessary for this purpose. These third parties are subject to the same obligations with regard to data protection as Swiss Post itself. In addition, data will be disclosed to third parties only within the parameters described in the sections above (e.g. IP addresses for analytics purposes). Disclosure to other companies within Swiss Post Ltd Group is ultimately permitted. Further details can be found in the relevant contracts, GTC or SC. We will retain your information for no longer than necessary and will treat it as confidential. This excludes the transmission of personal data to payment collection service providers, governmental institutions and authorities as well as to private persons with a right thereto based on statutory regulations, court orders or regulatory decisions, as well as its transfer to governmental institutions for the purposes of taking legal action or prosecution should our legally protected rights be challenged.

### 9\. Your rights

#### 9.1 Information, amendment, blocking and deletion/withdrawal of consent

You have the right to request information on the processing of your personal data and can request that it be amended, blocked or deleted.

If you have expressly consented to further data processing, you may revoke this at any time. Detailed information can be found in the relevant General Terms and Conditions and Subscriber Conditions. 

#### 9.2 Contact information

If you have questions, suggestions or concerns in relation to the handling of your data, you are welcome to contact us by post or e-mail:

Postal address: Swiss Post Contact Center, Post CH Network Ltd, Wankdorfallee 4, 3030 Bern, Switzerland

E-mail: [contactcenter@swisspost.ch](mailto:contactcenter@swisspost.ch)

Should you wish to contact us by e-mail, please note that e-mails are unencrypted and are therefore susceptible to the security risks typically associated with this method of communication.

### 10\. How secure is your data?

The data we collect and save is treated confidentially and, using appropriate technical and organizational precautions, protected against loss or manipulation as well as against unauthorized access by third parties.

Login information exchanged between your hardware and us is encrypted. We do not accept liability for any unauthorized access or loss of personal data that is beyond our control.

Our digital presence may contain links to other digital solutions which are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you access other digital solutions using the links provided, the operators of these digital solutions may collect information from you which will be used by these operators in accordance with their Privacy Policies, which may differ from ours.

### 11\. Changes to the Privacy Policy

Amendments to this Privacy Policy may be required from time to time; for example, due to the ongoing development of our digital presence or as a result of changes in legislation. Swiss Post therefore reserves the right to change the Privacy Policy at any time, with effect from a future date. Accordingly, we recommend that you reread this Privacy Policy on a regular basis.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on: 22 June 2021.

Disclaimer
----------

### Legal aspects

People (the “User” or “Users”) who access information on the Swiss Post Ltd website or when using the Post-App (the “Website”) agree to do so on the following conditions.

More information on Swiss Post Group can be found under “[About us](https://www.post.ch/en/about-us/profile/swiss-post-group-structure)”.

Please refer to the [privacy policy](https://www.post.ch/en/pages/footer/data-protection-and-disclaimer#data-protection) for queries relating to data protection.

### No binding offers

None of the items on the Website represent a binding offer.

### Exclusion of guarantee and liability

Swiss Post Ltd strives to provide information that is accurate and up to date at the time of its publication on the Website. However, Swiss Post Ltd does not guarantee and accepts no liability for the veracity, reliability, completeness and accuracy of this information, and reserves the right to update it at any time.

Such information is used at the Users’ own risk.

Where legally possible, Swiss Post Ltd accepts no liability for damage or consequential damage arising from access to and/or use of the Website or the inability to access or use the Website.

### Links

The Website may contain linked content that does not originate from Swiss Post Ltd, as well as links to websites or content owned by third parties that are in no way controlled or influenced by Swiss Post Ltd. Swiss Post Ltd accepts no liability for content of this kind, nor for the products, services or other offers which the respective third-party sites provide. Swiss Post Ltd also assumes no liability regarding websites that link to this Website or which use the information on this Website for their own purposes.

### Intellectual property rights

The entire contents of the Website are protected by copyright (all rights reserved). Downloading or printing out individual pages or parts of the Website is permitted provided that this is for private use and not for commercial purposes. No copyright notices or other legally protected names or symbols may therefore be removed.

Complete or partial reproduction, transmission (by electronic or any other means), modification or linking of the Website for public or commercial purposes is prohibited without the prior written consent of Swiss Post Ltd.

### Applicable law and place of jurisdiction

To the extent admissible by law, all legal relationships between the Users of the Website and Swiss Post Ltd shall be subject to substantive Swiss law. The sole place of jurisdiction is Bern.

Phishing and attempted fraud on the Internet
--------------------------------------------

The increasing number of attempts at fraud on the Internet deliberately target any carelessness on the part of users in order to gain access to coveted data. Here you will find information on what you and Swiss Post can do about them, and where you can report suspicious cases.

Rich Content Section
--------------------
